Guide to the Conference of Non-governmental Organizations in Consultatvive Status with the UN Economic and Social Council Records
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Conference of Non-governmental Organizations in Consultatvive Status with the UN Economic and Social Council Records
1948-1985.
Conference of Non-governmental Organizations in Consultative Status with the United Nations Economic and Social Council.
13 linear ft (ca. 14,000 items in 28 boxes).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
4078664
This collection contains correspondence, conference notes, studies, memoranda, documents, and related materials pertaining to the organization and operations of the Conference of Non-Governmental Organizations.
Historical Note
The Non-governmental Organizations are related to the United Nations through the Economic and Social Council of the General Secretariat, either in terms of administrative/financial support given by the U.N. and/or their potential use in the U.N.. NGOs usually run complementary conferences along with the U.N. on pertinent subjects, and also present declarations or reports at the U.N. conferences.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, conference notes, studies, memoranda, documents, and related materials pertaining to the organization and operations of the Conference of Non-Governmental Organizations. These records consist of files such as General conferences, New York Bureau meetings, study groups, UNICEF, Population conferences, International Social Service, Women, Human Rights, and Disarmament.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in two series:
Series I: 1971 Gift
Series II: 1988 Addition
Subjects
UNICEF.; United Nations.; Social service.; Women.; Civil rights.; Population.; Disarmament.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
02/07/1989 M-89-02-07 Evans, Luther & Rosalind Harris Gift, 1988
Gift of Luther Evans, 1971.
Gift of Rosalind Harris, 1988.
- Series I: 1971 Gift
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Interim Committee, 1948-50, Minutes and Documents (Box 2)
  - General Conferences (Box 2-4)
  - New York Bureau, Meetings
    - 1951-53 (Box 4)
    - 1954 -59 (Box 5)
  - European Meetings (Box 5)
  - Study Group-Article 71 (Box 6)
  - General Consultations (Box 6)
  - Inter-Organization Relationships (Box 6)
  - Legal Status (of NGOs) (Box 6)
  - Mailing Lists (Box 6)
  - Organizational Representatives for General Documentation (Box 7)
  - NGO Hearings-1954 (Box 7)
  - Discrimination Conference-1955 (Box 7)
  - Specialized Agencies (Box 7)
  - International Organization Service Center (Box 7)
  - Questionnaires and Answers (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous Documents (Box 7)
- Series II: 1988 Addition
  - Ford Foundation (Funding of Women's Projects) (Box 8-10, Folder 1 to 13)
  - International Social Service
    - I.S.S. General Secretariat (Box 11-12, Folder 1 to 4)
    - International Council of Voluntary Agencies (Box 12)
    - Migrant Workers (Box 12)
    - Proposals (Box 12)
    - Reports (Box 13)
    - Unicef (Box 13)
    - Mychild (publication) (Box 13)
  - International Women's Tribune Center
    - Background Documents, 1983 (Box 14)
    - Board, (2 Folders) (Box 14)
    - Commonwealth Secretariat (Box 14)
    - Correspondence (Box 14)
    - Decade for Women (Box 14)
    - Funding (Box 14)
    - Income and Expenses
      - General (Box 15)
      - Accountant's Reports (Box 15)
    - International Women's Rights Action Watch - Planning Conference (Box 15)
    - Information/Resources, (2 Folders) (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
    - Nairobi Forum, 1985 (Box 16)
    - Networking (Box 16)
    - Personnel (Box 16)
    - Programme Highlights (Box 16)
    - Projects and Reports, (2 Folders) (Box 16)
    - Proposals (Box 16)
    - Resolutions (Box 16)
    - Rights of Women (workbook) (Box 16)
    - The Tribune (vols. 1-26, 30, 33, 34) (Box 17)
  - NGO
    - Disarmament, (4 Folders) (Box 18)
    - Human Rights Committee (Box 18)
    - Habitat Forum (Montreal) (Box 19)
      - Committee Memos and Notes/Minutes (Box 19)
      - Dispatches and Reports (Box 19)
      - Follow-up Conference (Box 19)
      - Haus-Rucker Urban Film Project (Box 19)
      - International Institute for Environment and Development (Box 19)
      - News (Box 19)
      - Papers Presented (Box 19)
      - Program Outlines and Information (Box 19)
      - Report on the Forum (Box 19)
      - Statements of Forum to UN Conference (Box 19)
      - UN Environment Program (Box 19)
      - UN General Assembly (Box 19)
    - NGO Population Conferences (Box 20)
      - ACC Ad Hoc Task Force (Box 20)
      - Arab Parliamentary Conference on Development and Population (Box 20)
      - Asian Forum of Parliamentarians on Population and Development (Box 20)
      - Correspondence (Box 20)
      - Draper Fund Report (Box 20)
      - Global Tomorrow Coalition (Box 20)
      - International Consultation of NGOs on Population Issues (Box 20)
      - Leadership Conference on Population, Resources and Environment (Box 20)
      - Miscellaneous Material, (2 Folders) (Box 20)
      - Miscellaneous Pamphlets and Articles (Box 20)
      - NGOs and Population in the UN (Box 20)
      - NGO Population Task Force (Box 21)
      - Population and Development (Box 21)
      - Population and Development Workshop (Box 21)
      - Population Commission (Box 21)
      - Population Conference 1984 - NGO (Box 21)
      - Population Issues, (2 Folders) (Box 21)
      - Population Misconceptions (publication) (Box 22)
      - Population Tribune, 1974, (3 Folders) (Box 22)
      - Special Session Committee (Box 22)
      - UN Fund for Population Activities, (2 Folders) (Box 22)
  - UN Decade for Women
    - Carnegie Corporation (Box 23)
    - International Materials (Box 23)
    - International Training & Research Institute for the Advancement of Women (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous Materials (Box 23)
    - News Articles (Box 23)
    - NGO Forums (Box 23)
    - Secretariat for Women in Development (Box 24)
    - Unicef Participation (Box 24)
    - World Conference
      - NGO Planning Committee (Box 24)
      - US Position (Box 24)
      - US Reports (Box 24)
  - UNICEF/NGO
    - 1966-85 (Box 25)
    - Board Meetings and Minutes, 1980-83 (Box 26)
    - Disabled Children (Box 26)
    - Heritage Foundation Report, 1983 (Box 26)
    - Infant Feeding (Box 26)
    - International Year of the Child (Box 26)
    - Members Material (Box 26)
    - National Organizations Advisory Board for Children (Box 27)
    - Overview and Policies (Box 27)
    - Rights of the Child (Box 27)
    - Rome Board (Box 27)
    - Rome Forum, 1984 (Box 28)
    - Street Children (Box 28)
    - Universal Children's Day, 1982 (Box 28)
    - Victims of Armed Conflict (Box 28)
    - also: UnFoldered Pamphlets and Bound Reports (Box 28)